i'm so tired these stairs go on and on and it's exhausting food tastes better after a little
exercise little sword please sure there should be a switch here
i don't think i've ever seen this chamber before and we saved a lot of time getting here
damn it what's wrong the decoration for my cross guard fell off why'd you have to be so rough with
it i didn't mean to break it that's not your fault it's been loose for a while now i tried tying it
on with string and gluing it but nothing worked oh well did it have some special purpose nope not
really it was a memento wasn't it memento yeah i guess in a way it was three years ago my sister
and i were new adventurers to learn the ropes of the dungeon we joined a group of gold strippers
gold strippers this castle was covered in gold way back when parties would get rich scraping off the
gold gold hmm another party already stripped this place clean let's see if they hit the inside too
okay
laios if there are monsters in there we're not ready to handle them yet
yeah but we can't make it back by ourselves either
would you look at that poor guy
eh the armor's all rusted that's what happens if you die in a place like this and no one finds you
over here look what i found
wonder how much we'd get for all this armor they're all in good condition we could sell them as is or
melt them down
the armor's alive it's a monster
we can't fight these come on
it broke
oh no
i killed it
anyway that's what happened and that's how i got this sword
but you died for it
it was my first death and for a while afterwards the sight of armor would freak me out
you know i've read books on living armor and not one of them mentions anything about their flavor
i wonder what they taste like
what do you think senshi how would you cook it
what you can't eat armor
living armor is a suit of armor controlled by magic it's not some creature
yeah i know but what about the leather of the straps
you ever try and eat leather it's damn near impossible to chew
go catch a monster less of a pain
if you're so hell-bent on eating armor you could always eat your own
that's a shame i guess eating living armor is out of the question
come on let's go
let's avoid fighting them if possible
we'll just run past them
i think we could do it easy they don't move that fast
that's true
what do you think sound good
sure
any one of them could move
so stay alert here we go
get going
they blocked us we can't get out of the way
They blocked us!
We can't get to the other door!
What do we do now?
There's only one thing we can do now!
Go back the other way as fast as we can!
Run for it!
They're unusually aggressive.
I wonder if we did something to tick them off.
That's silly.
They don't have any feelings.
They're empty suits of armor.
The only way to stop them is to find whoever it is that's controlling them.
If someone was controlling those things, I didn't see them.
Usually what happens is you get too close to them and then they attack.
But these ones, they move to block the door.
That means there could be something on the other side of that door they have to protect.
Like whoever or whatever is controlling them.
That's gotta be it.
It's the only explanation.
Then you think it might be a monster?
I don't know.
Maybe.
Normal folks wouldn't have access to magic that powerful.
What now?
Unless we can get past them and through that door, we're stuck.
We'll have to find the major whatever that's controlling the armor.
Once we take them out, that should break the spell.
Obviously.
I got it.
If three people distract the armor, one of us can sneak right on by and get through the door.
Good luck sneaking by.
Actually, I thought you'd do the sneaking since that's kind of your thing.
But fighting definitely isn't my thing.
Living armor doesn't have eyes or ears because it doesn't need them.
Stealth skills don't work on things that aren't alive.
They don't have eyes or ears.
Are you ready?
Let's do this!
Yeah!
Come on, you rusty buckets!
I'm right here!
Come and get me!
Ah!
Bad idea!
Don't fear, missy!
Ask them!
Oh!
As they're mad!
Ah!
Oh, fantastic. There's one in here, too.
This one looks different from the armor in the other room.
There doesn't seem to be anyone here doing the controlling.
I get the feeling this one's the strongest.
I can't call the others for help.
I'll have to fight this thing on my own and figure out what the armors are protecting.
I'll try chopping off an arm or a leg. Maybe that'll slow it down.
Oh, God tiny ass.
Oh, God.
Oh, God!
Damn it!
Oh...
Oh!
It was protecting its shield.
What the...
What's that stuck to it?
Wait, I've seen something like that before.
That's right.
It's a...
An egg case.
That's what it was protecting.
Eggs!
What kind of eggs are they?
Do they belong to whatever's controlling the armor?
Living armor doesn't have eyes or ears because it doesn't need them.
I knew it.
There's more to these things.
If it has no eyes or ears...
Why'd it bother picking up the helmet and straightening it?
Why'd it turn its head to track our movements?
Why's it got eggs?
I know why.
There's a creature in it!
There's no outside force controlling them.
They move instinctively and deliberately to protect its eggs.
They're alive!
That means they can be killed.
That means...
We can eat them.
Take this!
There's too many of them!
Oh, no!
Keep moving!
If you stop, you're dead!
Behind you!
Aslam!
Wait!
No!
They can share their parts?
Not fair!
How's that possible?
Hurry up, Lyos!
We're getting swarmed in here and things are moving fast!
It doesn't stop if you chop off its head.
But if it's a living thing, it can be killed.
My options are slashing at its organs,
make it bleed to death,
suffocate it, starve it.
What am I saying?
Those will take too long.
First things first,
I need to find out what kind of creature's inside.
Maybe it's a slime.
But they don't move with precision.
They just...
ooze.
Maybe it's a horde of insects.
No, I would have heard them scuttling around inside.
Maybe there's a big spider in the helmet
using its legs to move the armor.
I wonder if that last one's it.
I'm not gonna find out standing here.
I can't overpower it,
so I'll outsmart it.
Yeah, this'll do.
I'll draw its attention and get right up next to it.
I've got it.
Now, let's see.
It's empty.
If there's nothing here,
why'd that other one even bother picking its helmet up?
He's coming.
Uh-oh.
What do I do?
Wait.
How can it not see me hiding over here?
There's something about the helmet, then.
What's this?
What the heck?
It's a mollusk.
And right between the layers of plating.
That's why cutting parts off the armor didn't work.
There's a colony of these in it.
It's still looking for its head.
All right, then.
Here!
Now we're talking.
This must be filled with them.
Looks like they connect to each other at the joints,
then expand and contract like muscles to move around.
But which one laid the eggs?
Guess if they're hermaphrodites,
guess they all could have laid them.
Now's not the time to think about that.
Gimme!
Let go already!
Hey, guys!
Get over here!
Do we look like we can?
Huh?
What was that?
And why did they go chasing it?
Whoa!
So, it was a mage after all.
Nope, there was no mage.
This so-called living armor isn't controlled by magic,
but by the creatures inside.
Huh?
Check this out.
The armor has two layers,
and look what's sandwiched between them.
That makes the armor move.
In the armor,
these things link together.
They form groups that act just like the muscles do in our bodies.
On their own, they're weak.
But together, they use the armor like a structure,
and that
is how they can move like us.
They were aggressive with us
because we happened to show up after they laid their eggs.
Seriously?
Those icky things hatch from eggs?
Born from eggs!
Isn't that amazing?
And I'm the one who found out about their secrets?
Until now,
everyone thought living armor was controlled by magic.
Wait till we tell the world about them.
We're gonna blow some mines!
You see that?
How when he talks about monsters,
he gets crazy eyes?
Creeps me out.
Hey, don't be rude.
Senshi,
we can't eat the armor,
but I bet we can eat these guys.
They look pretty dang nutritious, don't they?
Huh?
There's no way anyone's eating that mysterious gooey gunk!
Oh, Marcel.
The first bite of a new food is always mysterious.
Where's your sense of adventure?
That's a stupid adventure!
I'll fix him up.
Never cooked him before,
so can't promise it'll be any good.
Aw, thank you, Senshi.
Hell no!
What if those things are loaded with poison?
I'm pretty sure any creature that poisonous
wouldn't bother with hiding in a suit of armor.
What the heck kind of meal do I make out of him?
See that part?
When I tried to pry it open with my hand,
it wouldn't open.
I ended up making a cut right along there.
It couldn't close after that.
You know how a mollusk has that adductor muscle thing
to close their shells?
That's what that is.
So these are like shellfish.
I got an idea.
We'll need to pry him out of the armor first.
Oh, no.
They drowned.
Guess we can't clean off the sand that way.
And they didn't come from the sea,
so maybe we don't need to.
Not sure if its organs are safe to eat,
so they're going in the trash.
I'll slice these ones up and make soup.
Then heat some oil,
add critter, season in the medicinal herbs for a stir-fry.
The helmet critter is steamed.
And these, classic style all the way.
It's ready!
What are you going to try first?
Uh, uh, soup, I guess.
Wait, does anyone have an antidote for food poisoning?
Well, it doesn't smell bad.
Pretty sure what I'm smelling is iron.
Lyos.
Why is everyone looking at me like that?
You wanted to eat living armor,
so there it is.
Eat up.
You discovered him.
You get the first bite.
Such an honor.
You leave his corpse if he dies, okay?
Okay.
Did he die?
It's delicious!
Oh, my God, the flavor!
It's so good!
It didn't taste like anything at first but then!
Oh, man!
How long does food poisoning take to make you sick?
Depends on the food.
Ah!
Not bad.
Could use a condiment or three, maybe.
How'd those come out?
Huh?
Uh...
Well, at least these were stir-fried with medicinal herbs.
Oh!
Mm.
Mm-hmm.
Uh, and?
It doesn't taste bad.
Uh...
Oh...
How is it, Marsil?
They...
kind of taste like mushrooms.
I know, right?
I'm trying the steamed ones next.
I bet these'll taste better than the grilled ones.
Wow.
Tastes like mold.
Guess the helmet stink got cooked into them.
What?
Here.
Hmm.
In all my years of eating monster in this here dungeon,
I never would have dreamed I'd eat critters like those.
I doubt anyone dreamed living armor was really a type of shellfish.
A weird type born from an egg case.
Wouldn't it be neat to see what they're like right when they hatch?
I bet they're so small you can barely see them.
As they mature, they form their outer shells and find others like them.
They figure out how to move, start exploring, make colonies.
Maybe they line up like we saw them right before they mate.
Something tells me they're hermaphrodites,
and the biggest, healthiest colony lays all the eggs.
Wait, I just thought of something.
Whenever I saw suits of armor holding hands,
I thought it was a dungeon prank,
but maybe that was a mating ritual.
Someone needs a nap.
I was scared of living armor for so long.
Turns out, it was just a fragile, delicious monster.
Hey, I'm sorry your old sword got broken.
That one's pretty neat, though.
Hmm.
Hey, Lyos.
If you're taking that,
want me to check it to make sure it's not cursed?
No! Don't trouble yourself!
It's not cursed at all, really!
Totally not cursed!
Like you can tell.
Don't blame me if it turns out you get cursed.
Wait up! I'm coming!
So, with a new sword in hand,
the journey continues.
And as they descend into the dungeon,
the other three have no idea
their party has gained a new member.
It's arock of death.
And is that a new demon?
Oh, H information.
This is a new demon quiER pharmacy.
What are you kidding me?